(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Shall we dance? Shall we dance?
今宵は二人 踊り明かそう
Tonight, let's dance the night away, the two of us.
夢の中へと 誘いましょう
I'll invite you into a dream.
Shall we dance? Shall we dance?
もっと近くへ おいでよ
Come a little closer.
恋の魔法を かけましょう
I'll cast a love spell on you.
アキロゼ 5周年 記念ライブ
Akirose 5th Anniversary Memorial Live
Historic ROUTE 5
静寂（しじま）の
From the depths...
底から
...of silence.
目覚めるその柱たち
Those pillars awaken...
時を越え
...transcending time.
深紅（しんく）の
Deep-crimson...
血潮が
...blood...
立ち上がる勇気を
...brings together the courage...
惹きあわせる
...to stand up.
煌く迷（めい）を
If you call the glittering confusion...
運命（さだめ）と呼ぶならば
..."fate"...
微笑む眼（め）で
...then with a smiling eye...
次の手を
...take the next step.
闇を欺いて
Deceiving the darkness,
刹那をかわして
dodging the moment,
刃すり抜け
slipping through the blades,
奴らの隙を突け
strike at their opening!
つらぬいた思いが
Your unyielding thoughts
未来を拓く
will open up the future.
Like a Bloody Storm
熱く Like a Bloody Stone
burning hot, like a Bloody Stone!
宿命に刻まれた因縁に
From the destiny engraved by fate,
浮き上がる消えない誇りの絆
the bonds of indestructible pride emerge.
握りしめて
Grip them tight!
漲（みなぎ）る
With overflowing...
力に
...power,
打ち付ける鼓動は
the pounding heartbeat
共鳴（とも）の声
is the voice of resonance.
滲（にじ）んだ
With the seeping...
痛みと
...pain,
今生き抜く意味を
exchanging the meaning
交わしながら
of surviving now.
お前の意志が
Your will
夜明けを導く
shall lead to the dawn.
まばゆい程
With a dazzling...
気高さで
...nobility.
光射す丘へ
To the sun-drenched hill,
灼熱の空へ
to the scorching sky,
魂がぶつかりあう旅路へ
on a journey where souls collide!
悲しみに塗（ぬ）られた
Save the future
未来を救え
that's been painted in sadness.
Like a Bloody Soul
燃やせ Like a Bloody Star
burn it up, like a Bloody Star!
炎裂き風を断ちその先へ
Rending the flames, cutting through the wind, go beyond!
恐れずに何も躊躇（ためら）わず進め
Move forward without fear or hesitation.
流れの中
Through the flow of time...
共鳴（とも）にする　運命（さだめ）の波紋
...the ripples of fate resonate together.
心に
In my heart...
闇を欺いて
Deceiving the darkness,
刹那をかわして
dodging the moment,
刃すり抜け
slipping through the blades,
奴らの隙を突け
strike at their opening!
つらぬいた思いが
Your unyielding thoughts
未来を拓く
will open up the future.
Like a Bloody Storm
熱く Like a Bloody Stone
burning hot, like a Bloody Stone!
宿命に刻まれた因縁に
From the destiny engraved by fate,
浮き上がる消えない誇りの絆
the bonds of indestructible pride emerge.
握りしめて
Grip them tight!
はぁ～！
Phew!
アローナ！
Alona!
見えてる？聞こえてる？
Can you see me? Can you hear me?
ふーっ、はっ。待ってね。
(Heaving) Wait a second.
はい！ホロライブ1期生の癒し系ハーフエルフ、アキロゼ...
Okay! The healing half-elf of Hololive 1st Gen, Aki Rose...
アキロゼことアキロゼッタールです！
I'm AkiRoze, also known as Aki Rosenthal!
アローナ！
Alona!
ということで、アキロゼ５周年ライブ始まりました！イエーイ！
And so, AkiRoze's 5th anniversary live has begun! Yay!
今日はね、あの最高にね、かっこいいライブ、
Today, you know, it's the coolest live ever.
もう最後まで大注目なので、しっかり目に焼き付けてね！
Please keep your eyes glued to the screen until the very end!
そして、じゃじゃーん！こちらハッシュタグが載せてあるんだけど、
And, ta-da! I've put up the hashtag here.
#アキロゼ５周年Live で、あの、いっぱいツイートしてね！
Please tweet a lot with #AkiRoze5thAnniversaryLive!
可愛いスクショとか、可愛いね、切り抜きの
Please tweet lots of cute screenshots
ちっちゃい動画、短めの動画とか、いっぱいツイートしてください！
and cute short clips!
トレンド、目指せトレンド１位！
Let's aim for #1 on trending!
お願いします！
Please!
そしてね、さっきド派手に登場してくれた相棒がこちらになります。
And here is the buddy who made a flashy entrance earlier.
イエーイ！
Yay!
こちらアメ車のアキちゃん号です！
This is my American car, Akichan-gou!
ちょっとね、後ろの壁壊しちゃったんで、後で弁償します。
I accidentally broke the wall behind me, so I'll pay for the damages later.
はい。
Yes.
ということで、まだまだ始まったばかり、最後まで楽しんでください！
So, it's just getting started. Please enjoy until the end!
じゃあ、そろそろアキロゼ衣装チェンジしちゃおうかな？
Now, I think it's about time for an outfit change?
じゃあ着替えるから、ちょっとあっち向いてて。
I'm going to change, so please look away for a bit.
キャー！
Kyaa!
まだ見ていいって言ってないのに！エッチ！
I didn't say you could look yet! Pervert!
なんちゃって。
Just kidding.
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
こちらアワ・ブライト・パレードでね、みんな着た
This is the idol outfit we all wore for
アイドル衣装です！可愛い！
'Awa Bright Parade'! So cute!
そして、およよよ？なんとこの帽子は、
And, oh? Look at this hat,
なんか可愛いの付いてるよね？
it's got something cute on it, right?
一体何なんだろうか？
I wonder what it is?
気になるね、気になるよねー？
It's curious, isn't it?
ということで！
So!
それじゃあ次の曲行ってみよう！
let's head to the next song!
ゲストは、先ほど一緒に登場したフブキちゃん、
The guests are Fubuki-chan,
まつりちゃん、メルちゃーん！
Matsuri-chan, and Mel-chan!
イエーイ！
Yay!
Plasmagic Seasons!
歌：アキ・ローゼンタール、白上フブキ、夏色まつり、夜空メル
Vocals: Aki Rosenthal, Shirakami Fubuki, Natsuiro Matsuri, Yozora Mel
輝く夜空 瞬（ときめ）き送って
Sending a twinkle through the shining night sky
春風 君を乗せて 夏色が迎えるよ
Carrying you on the spring breeze, the colors of summer will greet you
色めく秋が 背中を押したら
Once the colorful autumn gives you a push
もふもふ 吹雪き煌めき 巡り巡る ほとり
Near the fluffy, glittering blizzard, as the seasons go round and round
何にもわからない 一歩進んで
Taking a step forward without knowing anything
やっとここまで 辿り着いたね
We've finally made it this far
街は見てる ずっと
The city's been watching all along
素敵なステージ 一番に
On this wonderful stage, the best of all
絶対見せてあげるよ
I'll definitely show you!
Because Smile, Smile, Catch Your Future!
無邪気に回る季節が
As the seasons turn innocently
世界を駆け巡って 夢のような日々へと
Running through the world, towards days like a dream
Hikare Bright, Bright, Light Up Future!
僕らが射し出すパワーで
With the power that we shine out
照らし続けよう
Let's keep on illuminating
スポットライトは 点（つ）いたばかり
The spotlight has only just been turned on
赤らむ頬は イルミネーション
Rosy cheeks are like illumination
心は彩りどりに 弾け舞うフェスティバル
Hearts are colorful, a festival bursting into dance
幸せいっぱい 注ぐロゼグラス
A rose-colored glass poured full of happiness
鳴らして キラリ染めるよ 真っ新（さら）な気持ち
Clink them together, dyeing a brand-new feeling with sparkle
十二時の鐘なんて 忘れちゃって
Just forget about the twelve o'clock bell
ずっと解けない 魔法かけよう
I'll cast a spell that will never be broken
時を回して Go Go
Turn back time, Go Go
胸躍る時間を
As I give you this
贈るから
heart-pounding time
絶対ついておいでよ
You definitely have to come along!
Todoke Puff, Puff, Make Our Future!
今を駆け抜ける五つ星
Five stars running through the present
世界も巻き込んで 賑やかに遊ぼう
Involving the whole world, let's play boisterously
Get up Brave, Brave, Move Our Future!
目まぐるしいシチュエーション
In this dizzying situation
まだ踊り足りないでしょう
You probably haven't danced enough yet, right?
カーテンコールはずっとずっと先まで
The curtain call is still a long, long way off
フッフー！
Woo-hoo!
盛り上がっていこう！
Let's get hyped!
こんこんきーつね！
Kon-kon-kitsune!
お祭りワッショイ！
Matsuri wasshoi!
みんな、5周年おめでとう！
Everyone, happy 5th anniversary!
そしてありがとう！
And thank you!
ハチャメチャ、また5人で歌おうね！
Let's sing together as five again!
待ってるよ！
We're waiting for you!
戻ってこいよ！
Come back to us!
愛してるぜー！
We love you!
楽しむ気持ちさえ 持ってきたら
If you just bring a sense of fun
きっと誰もが 主役になれるよ
Surely everyone can be the main character
羽もしっぽも 笑顔もさらけ出して
Bare your wings, your tail, and your smile
もっと Step Step もっと Jump Jump
More Step Step, more Jump Jump
もっと トラ・イ・コ の世界を
More, try this world
一緒に遊び尽くそう
Let's play together to the fullest
響け Clap Clap Let's see Future
Resound Clap Clap, Let's see Future
このメロディが終わっても 決して
Even if this melody ends
今日だけの思い出には しないよ
I won't let it be just today's memory
光る Smile Smile Catch our Future
Shining Smile Smile, Catch our Future
無邪気に回る季節が 世界を
The innocently spinning seasons will travel the world
駆け巡って夢のような 日々へと
Towards days like a dream
光る Fly Fly Like our Future
Shining Fly Fly, Like our Future
僕らが優等生さ
We are the honors students
さあ照らし続けよう
Now let's keep shining
スポットライトは終わらない
The spotlight never ends
はーい！
Yes!
ということで、1期生オリジナル曲の
「Plasmagic Seasons!」でしたー！
So, that was the 1st gen original song,
"Plasmagic Seasons!"
イェーイ！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you!
ということでね、登場の時はついてなかったものが、
実はあります！
So, there's actually something
that wasn't there when we first appeared!
おっ、ありますあります！
Oh, right, right!
何かな何かな？
I wonder what it is?
駅員さんですか？
Are you a station attendant?
プピピピポポー！
Beep-beep-beep-beep-boop!
これもついてるしね。
It has this on it too.
そう、可愛いんですけど、まあこの後ね、
引き続き見てくれれば一体何の帽子かなって…
Yes, it's cute, but if you keep watching
after this, you'll see what kind of hat it is...
オリャオリャオリャオリャ！
Orya-orya-orya-orya!
ちょっと帽子投げて使うわけじゃないですよ。
It's not like you throw the hat and then use it.
帽子投げていくものかと思った！
I thought it was something you throw!
惜しいんだけどね。惜しいんだよね。
Close, though. You're close.
まあちょっとだけ違うかな。
Well, it's a little bit different.
さあこの後もね、見てもらえれば
何かわかると思います！
Well, if you keep watching after this,
I think you'll understand!
なるほど！はい！
I see! Okay!
まあ、ということで5周年なんで、
1期生5周年、デビュー組が多いので、
Well, since it's the 5th anniversary, and many
1st gen members debuted around now,
今日はせっかくなんで改めて自己紹介と
何か宣伝とかがあればね、
today I'd like to do introductions again,
and if there's any announcements...
していきたいと思います。じゃあ、まつりちゃんお願い！
I'd like to do that. Matsuri-chan, go ahead!
はい！ホロライブの清楚担当、みんなのアイドル、
夏色まつりです！イェース！イェーイ！ワッショイ！
Yes! Hololive's purity representative, everyone's idol,
Natsuiro Matsuri! Yes! Yay! Wasshoi!
まつりはね、あのね、6月の3日に
3Dではないんですけど、ちょっと記念配信を…
On June 3rd, I'm planning
a commemorative stream, not in 3D, but...
予定しておりますので、お時間ある方、
ない方も時間作って見に来てください！お願いします！
So please come watch, even if you're busy!
Please! Thank you!
お願いしまーす！イェーイ！
Thank you! Yay!
はい、じゃあ続いてフブキちゃん！
Okay, next is Fubuki-chan!
あの挨拶をやるのは恥ずかしいので…
Since doing that greeting is embarrassing...
こんこんきーつね！白上フブキです！
ちょっと恥ずかし、恥ずかしいので…
Kon-kon-kitsune! I'm Shirakami Fubuki!
It's a little embarrass, embarrassing, so...
白上はですね、6月の23日にちょっとあの企画を
予定しておりますので、楽しみにしていただけると嬉しいです！
I have a project planned for June 23rd,
so I'd be happy if you look forward to it!
おー！なんだろう？何やるのかな？
Oh! I wonder what it is? What are you doing?
要望、とんでもないことですね！
とんでもないこと予定しておりますのでよろしくお願いします！
Something amazing! I'm planning
something big, so please look forward to it!
楽しみにしてワッショイ！はい、じゃあメルちゃん！
Looking forward to it, wasshoi! Okay, now Mel-chan!
こんかぷ！魔界の天才バンパイア、
ホロライブ1期生の夜空メルです！イェース！
Kon-kapu! The genius vampire from the underworld,
Hololive 1st gen Yozora Mel! Yes!
メルは5月13日に、あの、もう記念配信
させていただきまして、
I already had my commemorative stream
on May 13th,
アーカイブとね、グッズ販売してるので
よろしくお願いします！はーい！
so the archive and goods are available.
Please check them out! Yes!
お願いします！みんなのチャンネル登録も
お願いしますよ！お願いしますよー！
Please! And please subscribe
to everyone's channels too! Please do!
ということでこの帽子だけじゃなくて、
実はみんなにサプライズが…あります！
So, it's not just these hats,
there's actually a surprise for everyone!
えっ！？何！？お肉！？お肉！？
お肉じゃない！ついてきて！いくよ！
What!? What!? Meat!? Meat!?
It's not meat! Follow me! Here we go!
お肉お肉…お肉じゃないけどついてきて！
Meat, meat... it's not meat, but follow me!
こっちです！こっちです！はいはい！
焼肉じゃありませーん！
This way! This way! Okay!
It's not yakiniku!
焼肉じゃありませーん！焼肉おごってくださーい！
お肉ー！
It's not yakiniku! Please buy me yakiniku!
Meat!
プピピピポポー！はい、プピピ！
はいはいはい、どうぞどうぞ！
Beep-beep-beep-beep-boop! Yes, beep-beep!
Yes, yes, yes, this way, this way!
はいはいはい、広い！はーい！来ましたー！
Yes, yes, yes, it's huge! Yes! We're here!
おぉー！なぜ体育館！？何！？何ここ！？
なぜ体育館！？何すんの！？
Oh! Why the gym!? What!? What's this!?
Why the gym!? What are we doing!?
みんなちょっと運動不足じゃない？
Aren't you all a bit lacking in exercise?
そういうこと！？嘘！？
Is that it!? No way!?
まあそうですけど…
Well, yes, but...
今から、シャトルランをやってもらいます！イェーイ！
Now, I'm going to have you do a shuttle run! Yay!
いやだー！いやだー！無理だよー！
No way! No way! It's impossible!
無理無理無理無理！バスケはしたいよー！
No, no, no, no! I want to play basketball!
いいけど、あ、しょうがないの。じゃあ今日はね、まぁライブということで...
That's fine, but... oh well. So today, since it's a live concert...
まずは、ちょっとね、この広い体育館なんですけど後ろにね、見て、でっかいのあるでしょ。モニター！
First of all, in this spacious gym... Look behind me, there's something huge, right? A monitor!
でっかいモニターがあります。
There's a huge monitor.
これは何するんですか？
What are we going to do with this?
さあ、何でしょう。それではVTR、どうぞ！
Well, I wonder. Now then, please watch this VTR!
3月某日
スタッフはダンス練習後のアキロゼをつかまえた。
A certain day in March.
The staff caught Akirose after dance practice.
あ、こんちは～、お疲れ様ですぅ。
Ah, hello, good work today.
アキさん、もうすぐ5周年ですね。
Aki-san, it's almost your 5th anniversary.
5周年... 5周年かぁ。
5th anniversary... 5 years, huh.
すごい... すごいっすね... アキロゼ。
It's amazing... it's really something... Akirose.
活動を振り返ってみてどうですか？
Looking back on your activities, how do you feel?
いやぁ... まさか、
Well... honestly,
そうだなぁ。デビューした時は正直、
5周年とか迎えられると思ってなかったから。
I guess... when I debuted, I didn't think
I'd reach my 5th anniversary.
いま結構... 奇跡起きてるくらい
すごい事かもしれないって思うな。
I feel like it's almost a miracle
that I've come this far.
こうやって3D（配信）とかも、最初出来なくて。
I couldn't do things like 3D streams at first.
「夢」みたいな所があったから。
今こうやって出来るのが嬉しいかなぁ...
It felt like a "dream," so being
able to do it now makes me really happy...
感想深いですね... 泣けます。
That's very profound... I'm touched.
思ってないでしょ絶対！
You don't really mean that!
嘘つけぇ！
Liar!
今年の5周年はどんな事をするんですか？
What are you planning for this year's 5th anniversary?
えー、うわぁ、これ、そうだなぁ。
Hmm, wow, that's a tough one.
脳みそこねくり回しながらも、
一応ね、やりたいなって思ってる事があって...
While racking my brain,
there's something I've been wanting to do...
皆それぞれ青春時代はあるじゃないですか。
Everyone has their own "youthful days," right?
吹奏楽とマーチングバンド、どっちもやってる
There was a time when I was doing both
wind instruments and marching band,
アツい部活に打ち込んでいた時があって。
and was devoted to a very intense club.
やっぱりそれがアキロゼの青春そのものだったりとか。
That was truly the essence of Akirose's youth.
めげない、しょげない、諦めない、そういう強い精神を
I think I developed a strong spirit there—
そこで育てられたかなっていうのがあるんだよね～。
never discouraged, never down, never giving up.
そうなんですね...！じゃあ今年の5周年は...？
I see...! So for this year's 5th anniversary...?
なんかちょっと一緒に出来ないかな～、みたいな、こう...
I've wondered if I could do something together with them...
思った事はあるかなぁ...。
I have thought about it...
だから5周年、やっぱり結構大きい節目だし。
Since the 5th anniversary is a big milestone...
ちょっとなんか... 出来ないかなぁ...？
I was thinking, maybe I could...?
スタッフ達は内緒で
とあるマーチングバンドへオファーをお願いした。
The staff secretly
made an offer to a certain marching band.
4月某日
スタッフはアキロゼを東京駅に呼び出した。
A certain day in April.
The staff called Akirose to Tokyo Station.
あ、おはようございま～す。
Ah, good morning.
今日ってなんの仕事なんですか...？
What kind of work is it today...?
えぇ～... なんか怖いなぁ...
Ehh... I'm a bit scared...
車に揺られること1時間
An hour's ride in the car
たどり着いた先は...
The destination they arrived at was...
横浜市金沢産業振興センター！
Yokohama Kanazawa Industrial Promotion Center!
いや、どこココ～！？
Wait, where even is this!?
謎の施設に潜入？
誰が待っているのか
Sneaking into a mysterious facility?
Who is waiting there?
え、え、何...？
Eh, wait, what...?
体育館...？ど、ど... え、え？なんか聞こえる...
A gymnasium...? Wh-wh... Huh? I hear something...
ここってマーチングバンドチームですよね...？
This is a marching band team, isn't it...?
アキさん、以前コラボしたいって仰ってたじゃないですか？
Aki-san, didn't you say before that you wanted to collaborate with one?
「ヨコハマロビンズ」の皆様です！
It's the "Yokohama Robins"!
いい～！？
Really!?
えぇ... すごい...
Whoa... amazing...
ヨコハマロビンズ：中学生から社会人で構成される
1990年創立の強豪マーチングバンドチーム
Yokohama Robins: A powerful marching band team founded in 1990,
composed of members from middle schoolers to working adults.
全国大会に2000年から23年連続出場と
数々の経歴をもっている。
They have an impressive history, including
23 consecutive appearances in the national competition since 2000.
紅白で福山雅治氏とのコラボのほか、CM出演や
映画出演と幅広い活躍をしている有名チーム！
A famous team with a wide range of activities, including collaborating
with Masaharu Fukuyama on Kohaku, appearing in commercials and movies!
実はアキロゼも憧れていた夢のマーチングバンド！
In fact, they are the dream marching band that Akirose has always admired!
ほんと？ほんと？
Really? Really?
もう大体のお話は出来てるのでご挨拶お願いします
The arrangements are mostly made, so please go ahead and greet them.
え！今！？今ですか？
Eh! Now!? Right now?
お～練習してる... やぁいいな～かっこいい...
Oh, they're practicing... Wow, so cool...
なんか話しかけられそうな人が... いくか...！
Looks like someone I can talk to... Here I go...!
あの～！こんにちは！
Um, hello!
お忙しいところお邪魔してます！
Sorry to interrupt while you're busy!
私、アキ・ローゼンタールと申しまして... 本日お話しさせていただく時間もらって...
I'm Aki Rosenthal... I was told I'd have some time to talk today...
はい聞いております！アキさんですね！お待ちしておりました！
Yes, we've heard! You're Aki-san, right! We've been waiting for you!
メンバー！集合してください！集合ー！
Members! Please gather round! Everyone, assemble!
集合...？
Assemble...?
おわ～！めっちゃ集まってきた！
Whoa! So many people are gathering!
本日アキ・ローゼンタールさんがいらっしゃってますのでご挨拶したいと思います。気をつけ、礼！
Aki Rosenthal-san is here today, so we'd like to greet her. Attention, bow!
こんにちは
Hello.
こんにちは！
Hello!
あ、こ、こんにちは～！
Ah, h-hello~!
みなさん初めまして！
Nice to meet you all!
ホロライブのアキ・ローゼンタールと申します！
I'm Aki Rosenthal from Hololive!
めちゃくちゃ団員さんいっぱいいる…
Wow, there are so many members...
ちなみに現在何名くらいいらっしゃるんですか？
By the way, how many members are there currently?
ちょうど4月の入れ替わりの時期なんですが、
It's just the transition period in April,
現在130名在籍していて、
but we currently have 130 members registered,
今日はほぼ全メンバー揃ってます！
and almost all members are here today!
すごい！ありがとうございます！
Amazing! Thank you!
せっかくの機会なので色々お伺いしたいんですけれども、
Since I have this opportunity, I'd like to ask a few things.
まずお二人はどういった方なのか教えてもらってもいいですか？
First, could you tell me a bit about yourselves?
僕はこのチームメンバーを統括している知野亮太郎といいます！
I'm Ryotaro Chino, and I manage the team members here!
いわばこのバンド全体のリーダーというような役職をやっています。
I basically serve as the overall leader of this band.
私もこのバンドのリーダーを務めている荒井春南です！
I'm also a leader of this band, Haruna Arai!
なるほど、ありがとうございます！
Ah, I see, thank you!
ちなみにお二人はなんの楽器を担当しているんですか？
By the way, which instruments do you both play?
僕はですね、この大きなチューバという金管楽器を担当しています。
Well, I play this large brass instrument called the tuba.
実は私は楽器ではないんですけども、
Actually, I don't play an instrument, but...
マーチング特有のカラーガードというダンサーの役割を担っています。
...I perform as a color guard, a dancer role unique to marching bands.
実はアキロゼもカラーガードをほんのちょっとだけやっていたことがあります！
Actually, Akirose also did color guard for a little bit a long time ago!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
ちなみにホルンもやってました～！
By the way, I also played the horn~!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
ぜひこの後見学させて欲しいです！
I'd definitely love to observe your practice later!
たくさんのメンバーさんがいらっしゃるので、
Since there are so many members here,
ちょっとひとつ聞いてみたいことがあるんですが、いいですか？
there's one thing I'd like to ask. Is that okay?
ホロライブって知ってますか？
Do you know what Hololive is?
知ってる人手をあげてくださ～い！
If you know it, please raise your hands~!
おお、ちょっといる！！
Oh, quite a few people!!
いろはちゃん！
Iroha-chan!
さてはかざま隊おるな！
So there's a Kazama-tai member here!
リーダーのお二人も手をあげてるじゃないですか！
Even the two leaders have their hands up!
ちなみに誰推しか聞いてみてもいいですか…？
By the way, can I ask who your oshi is...?
はい、僕は白上フブキちゃん推しです！
Yes, I'm a Shirakami Fubuki fan!
私は白銀ノエルちゃんです！
I'm a Shirogane Noel fan!
あぁ そうなんですねぇ… うんうんうん、可愛いもんね。
Ah, I see... Yeah, yeah, they are cute.
ちなみにあのぉアキロゼのファンは…？
By the way, um, are there any Akirose fans...?
ちょ、手あげて…？
Please raise your hands...?
ちょっと恥ずかしい感じかな？
Is it a bit embarrassing?
やっぱ手を上げるのって恥ずかしいことだもんね。うんうんうん。
I guess raising your hand is embarrassing. Yeah, yeah.
えっとあの！ あの～
Um, so! Well...
実は今日お願いがあって来ました～…
The truth is, I came here today with a request~...
そのお願いは聞いてもらっていいですか？
Could you hear me out?
はい！
Sure!
ずっと夢があって
I've always had a dream.
マーチングバンドさんがずっとずっと大好きなんですけれども、
I've always loved marching bands, but...
それこそヨコハマロビンズさん、ずーっと追っかけ、ファンで…
I've been a huge fan of Yokohama Robins for a long time...
一緒にパフォーマンスをしてみたいって思ってたんですよね…！
...and I've always wanted to perform with you!
なので！ 今度アキロゼの5周年ライブがあるんですが、
So! I have my 5th anniversary live coming up,
そこでホロライブの曲コラボとかやっていただくことって可能でしょうか……？
and I was wondering if it's possible for us to collaborate on a Hololive song there...?
はい！是非！一緒にやりましょう！
Yes! Absolutely! Let's do it together!
お！本当ですか！？
Oh! Really?!
ありがとうございます！！
Thank you so much!!
と、いうことでなんと！
And so, believe it or not!
YOKOHAMA ROBINSさんとのコラボが決定しました！
The collaboration with Yokohama Robins has been confirmed!
まさかロビンズさんと一緒にパフォーマンスできる日が来るなんて思ってもなかったです。
I never imagined the day would come when I could perform with the Robins.
一生懸命練習を重ねてきました。
I've been practicing very hard.
1期生のみんな、一緒に歌ってくれるよね！
My fellow 1st generation members, you'll sing with me, right?
ロゼ隊のみなさんにも見て欲しいです！
I want all the Rosetai to see this too!
ロビンズのみなさ～ん！
Everyone in the Robins~!
いきますよ～！
Here we go~!
一緒にがんぼ～？
Let's give it our best together...?
ローゼ！！
Rose!!
うぇ～い！
Waaaay!
マジかー！
No way!
すごーい！
Amazing!
嬉しいね！
I'm so happy!
嬉しい！
Happy!
はい！初の試みかな？と思います。
Yes! I think this might be a first-time attempt.
はい、ということで今日は、なんとですね！
Yes, and so today, believe it or not!
ヨコハマロビンズさんの体育館と、このバーチャル体育館の中継が繋がっています！
We have a live link between the Yokohama Robins' gym and this virtual gym!
ロビンズのみなさーん！
Everyone in the Robins!
こんにちは！
Hello!
お久しぶりです！
It's been a while!
ということで今日は、1期生のみんなとロビンズさんと一緒にパフォーマンスコラボしちゃいます！
And so today, we're doing a performance collaboration with my fellow 1st gen members and the Robins!
イェーイ！
Yay!
私たちも一緒～！ありがとうございます！
We're together too~! Thank you so much!
ロビンズさんにオリジナル編曲してもらったホロライブのあの曲を一緒にパフォーマンスしちゃいたいと思います！
We're going to perform that Hololive song with an original arrangement by the Robins!
でも、その前に、せっかくの機会なのでロビンズさんが、
But before that, since we have this opportunity, the Robins...
どんなにかっこいいか
To show you how cool they are,
いつも公園で見せてくれるパフォーマンス、
the performance they always show at the park...
見てみたくない？
Don't you want to see it?
見たい！見たい見たい！
I want to see it! Yes, definitely!
ということで副隊長の知野さん！
So, Deputy Leader Chinou-san!
パフォーマンス見せていただくことってできますかね？
Would you be able to show us a performance?
はい、ぜひ見ていただきたいです。
Yes, I'd definitely like you to see it.
おおー！やったー！楽しみ！
Ooh! Yay! I'm so excited!
頑張ります。
We'll do our best.
それでは準備いたしますね。
Now, we will get ready.
はーい、よろしくお願いします！
Okay, please do!
よろしくお願いします！楽しみー！
We're looking forward to it!
や、すごいねー。
Wow, this is amazing.
ワクワク。
So excited.
みんなさ、見たことある？そのマーチングバンドって。
Have you guys ever seen a marching band before?
ないない！ないかも。
No, never! I don't think so.
ないです。ねー。
I haven't either. Yeah.
かっこいいよね。
It's cool, right?
ねー、めちゃめちゃかっこいい！
Yeah, it's so incredibly cool!
で、この帽子も実はさ、
And actually, these hats...
あ、そっか！
Oh, that's right!
マーチングバンドの帽子をね、
They're marching band hats,
意識しております。
we were inspired by them.
ね、かっこいいよね。かっこいいでしょ？
They look great, don't they?
ね、ピッピッと。
Yeah, with that 'pi-pi-pi' sound.
ピッピピッピか。そのピッピッか！
The 'pi-pi-pi-pi'? Oh, that's what you meant!
あ、そういうことだった？えー。
Oh, is that what it was? Wow.
お、そろそろ？お？
Oh, is it almost time? Oh?
準備が、あ、できましたか？
Is the preparation... Oh, is it ready?
お、来ましたか？
Oh, is it starting?
はい、じゃあそろそろ準備ができたみたいなので、
Okay, it looks like they're ready now, so...
お、やった！それでは見させていただきますか！
Oh, yay! Let's go ahead and see it then!
はい！はーい！お願いします！
Yes! Okay! Please do!
ワクワク。
So excited.
かっこいい。
So cool.
かっこいいね。
It's cool, isn't it?
すごい、聞こえてる。
Amazing, I can hear it.
ね、デッカいでしょう？
Yeah, it's massive, right?
かっこいいなー。
It's so cool.
うぉー！
Whoa!
いいねー。
Nice.
わ、すごい。
Wow, amazing.
めちゃ足揃ってる！
Their steps are perfectly in sync!
本当だ、すげー！
You're right, that's amazing!
すごい。
Incredible.
踊ってたんだ。
They're even dancing.
はい。
Yes.
聞いたことある曲だよ。
I know this song.
いい曲だねー。
It's a great song.
おー、かっこいいなー。
Oh, that's so cool.
わ、速い！めちゃすご！
Wow, so fast! That's incredible!
わ、かっこいい！
Wow, so cool!
スッと揃うのいいね。
I love how they align so quickly.
わ、すごい！カラーガードチームが。
Wow, amazing! The color guard team...
綺麗！わー！
Beautiful! Wow!
実はアキロゼもちょっとやってたんだよ、カラーガード。
Actually, Akirose used to do color guard too.
あ、そうなんだ！
Oh, really!
書き換えるのかっこよすぎる。
The way they switch is too cool.
ねー。
Yeah.
惚れちゃいそう！ねー。
I might fall in love! Right?
すごい！そのまま後ろ下がれるのすごい！
Incredible! Moving backwards like that is amazing!
ねー！すごーい！
Yeah! So cool!
おー！凄ーい！
Oh! Amazing!
わ、見せ場きたー！
Wow, here comes the showcase!
すごい！
Amazing!
130人いるからね。
There are 130 people in total.
すごいねー。一糸乱れぬ。
That's incredible. Perfectly in sync.
わー！かっこいい！凄ーい！
Wow! So cool! Amazing!
ヨコハマロビンズスペシャルパフォーマンス、
Yokohama Robins special performance,
『マイウェイ』でした！
'My Way'!
いぇーい！
Yay!
本当に最高だったので、
That was truly the best,
ちょっとリーダーたちに話を聞いてみたいと思うんですが、
so I'd like to talk to the leaders for a bit...
新井さん、知野さん、ちょっとお話聞かせてもらってもいいですか？
Arai-san, Chinou-san, would it be alright to ask you a few things?
はーい！うぉー！
Yes! Whoo!
わー、ありがとうございます！
Wow, thank you so much!
本当に素敵な演奏ありがとうございました。
Thank you truly for such a wonderful performance.
ホロライブの他の1期生のメンバーからも、
Also, from the other 1st generation members of Hololive...
メンバーにもうちょっと感想聞いてみたいと思うんだけど...
I'd like to hear some more impressions from the members...
フブキちゃん、どうだった？
Fubuki-chan, how was it?
いや、もう、ほんと、めちゃめちゃ動き揃っててかっこよかったです。
No, really, their movements were so perfectly in sync and cool.
めちゃめちゃよかったです！ありがとうございます！
It was amazing! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
えー、すごかったね。
Man, that was incredible.
じゃ、メルちゃんは？
And how about you, Mel-chan?
皆さんの呼吸の合った動きや演奏、最高でした！
Everyone's perfectly synchronized movements and performance were the best!
うーん！よかった！
Yeah! It was great!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ね、じゃ、まつりちゃん、どうだった？
Right, so Matsuri-chan, how was it?
あの、チューバ、でっかい楽器の人、すごい重そうなのに...
Um, the person with the tuba, that huge instrument, it looks so heavy...
いや、そんな大きい物持てたら、まあ、まつりちゃんも余裕で持ち上げられちゃいますよね？
Well, if you can carry something that big, then I guess you could easily lift up Matsuri-chan too, right?
頑張ります！
I'll do my best!
安心してください。太っていきます！
Don't worry. I'm going to get fat!
痩せない！やめろ！ダイエットしようよ！
Don't! Stop! Let's go on a diet!
アキロゼも一緒にね、持ち上げてもらおうと思います。
I think I'll have them lift up AkiRose together with her.
ロビンズの皆さん、改めてありがとうございました。
Robins, thank you again very much.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ところで、ちょっと聞きたいんですけど...
By the way, there's something I want to ask...
あの、以前ね、他のホロライブのメンバーは、なんか、ちょっと、好きだーって聞いてたんですけど...
Um, before, I heard that you guys liked other Hololive members...
そうだそうだ！
That's right, that's right!
アキロゼ推しになりましたかー？
Have you become AkiRose fans?
ちょっと確認したいなーと思って。
I just wanted to check.
あ、ライさん。アキロゼのこと、好きになりました？
Oh, Rai-san. Did you come to like AkiRose?
なりました。
I did.
わー！やったー！嬉しいー！
Wow! Yay! I'm so happy!
カラーガード大好きなんで、ね、これからもいっぱいよろしくお願いします。
I love the color guard, so please continue to support me.
ちゅっちゅっちゅっちゅっ！
Kiss kiss kiss kiss!
じゃあ、ちょっとお隣の、エチノさん？はどうですかね？
Then, how about the person next to you, Echino-san?
もちろん推しになりました。キュンです！
Of course you've become my oshi. I'm smitten!
わー！嬉しいー！
Wow! I'm so happy!
え、でも、じゃあ、アキロゼのこと好きだったら、「アキロゼ大好きだよ！」って言ってもらってもいいですか？
Wait, if you like AkiRose, could you say "I love you, AkiRose!"?
アキロゼ、大好きだよ！
AkiRose, I love you!
わー！なんて声を！
Wow! What a voice!
もう一回お願いします！
One more time, please!
アキロゼ、大好きだよ！
AkiRose, I love you!
ちょいちょい！
Hold on!
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
ちょっとね、私利私欲も見たいだ、見たいところで...
I just wanted to see a bit of my own self-interest fulfilled...
皆さん、ありがとうございます。
Thank you, everyone.
さあ、いよいよ、マーチングバンドとホロライブのコラボレーションが、ついに実現だー！
Now, at last, the collaboration between the marching band and Hololive is finally happening!
わー！
Yay!
5周年を祝って、皆で一緒に歌おう！
To celebrate the 5th anniversary, let's all sing together!
ロビンズの皆さん、それでは、準備お願いいたします！
Robins, please get ready!
お願いいたしまーす！
Please!
なー！マーチングかっけー！
Man! Marching is so cool!
本当にかっこよかった！最高だったね！
It was really cool! It was the best!
もうね、かっこいいパフォーマンスも見たし...
Well, we've seen a cool performance...
まあ、なんかアキロゼ推しもできたし。
...and I've gained some AkiRose fans.
何かさ、すごい言わせてたし。
You were totally making them say that.
言わせてたよね！
You were, weren't you!
ないないないちょっと。ないないない。
No, no, no. Not at all.
本音本音本音。
True feelings, true feelings.
圧かかってたって！
You were pressuring them!
かけたつもりはなかったんだけどな。
I didn't mean to pressure them, though.
まあでも、フブキちゃん推しだし。
Well, but they're Fubuki-chan fans.
そうだよ、まつりちゃん推しだったよ。
That's right, they were Matsuri-chan fans.
なんやねん。
What's that supposed to mean?
でも、一緒にやった仲だからね、ごめんね。
But since we've worked together now, sorry about that.
そうそうそう、そういうことだよ。しょうがない、しょうがない。
Exactly, that's how it is. Can't be helped, can't be helped.
仲良しだね。
You're so close.
ということでね、じゃあ、私達もそろそろ、えー、コラボパフォーマンスの準備していきましょうか！
So, shall we also start getting ready for our collaboration performance!
わー！やったー！
Yay! Alright!
ちょっとスペシャルなんですけど、まあ、いつものようにね...
It's a bit special, but as always...
はい。笑顔で、可愛く、元気に、愛を持って...
Yes. With smiles, cutely, energetically, and with love...
スーパーアイドルお届けしちゃってくださいね！
Please deliver a super idol performance!
はーい！任せろ！
Okay! Leave it to us!
本当はね、ここね、一緒に、えっと、はあちゃまもやりたかったんだけどね...
Actually, I wanted Haachama to be here with us too...
復活待ってるからね！待ってるよ！はあちゃま！
We're waiting for your return! We're waiting, Haachama!
よし、それじゃあ皆やるぞー！
Alright, let's do this, everyone!
おー！
Yeah!
ということで、それでは、横浜ロビンズさんとのスペシャル生バンドコラボレーション...
And so, please listen to our special live band collaboration with the Yokohama Robins...
「Our Bright Parade」、聴いてください！
"Our Bright Parade"!
Our Bright Parade / 作詞・作曲：堀江晶太
Our Bright Parade / Lyrics & Composition: Shota Horie
パレード パレード パレード 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, let it shine
呼び合う声も合図に
With our calling voices as a signal
パレード パレード パレード 探しに行く
Parade, parade, parade, let's go search
スタートは何度だって
The start is however many times it takes
ラララ...
Lalala...
始まりたくて走った
I ran because I wanted to begin.
遠く暗がりに灯った
It was lit up in the distant darkness.
それは眩しすぎた名前
That name was too dazzling.
それは優しすぎた思い出
That memory was too kind.
もっと
More...
近づけと手を伸ばした
...I reached out to bring it closer.
思いがけず結び合ったら
When we unexpectedly became connected...
ほら今 My Bright Parade 鳴りました
Look, now My Bright Parade has begun!
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's shining!
悔しさも愛おしさも連れておいで
Bring your frustrations and your affections along.
風呼んで羽 飛び立てるさ
Call the wind, and we can fly away.
ささやかな祈りは光 終わりなき兆し
A humble prayer is light, a never-ending sign.
君を見つけたこと胸を張れるよ
I can be proud that I found you.
ここから これから Our Bright Parade Parade
From here on, from now on, Our Bright Parade, Parade.
ただいまを聞けば お帰りと叫ぶよ
When I hear "I'm home," I'll shout "Welcome back!"
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't it only natural?
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! It's shining!
悔しさも愛おしさも連れておいで
Bring your frustrations and your affections along.
風呼んで羽 飛び立てるさ
Call the wind, and we can fly away.
ささやかな祈りは光 終わりなき兆し
A humble prayer is light, a never-ending sign.
君と飛び込んでゆく ステラな高さ
Diving in with you to stellar heights.
ここから これから Our Bright Parade Parade
From here on, from now on, Our Bright Parade, Parade.
Our Bright Parade Parade
イェーイ！
Yay!
最高！
That was great!
楽しかった！
So much fun!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
Thank you!
キミにまつわる運命事情
The Destiny Surrounding You
今日は絶好調 そのはずでした滑稽
Today I was in top form... or so I thought. How comical.
天気予報ド外れ
The weather forecast was completely off.
ドア閉まるバス 憂鬱 Monday
Bus doors closing, a gloomy Monday.
なんて不条理 文句誰行き？
How irrational. Who can I complain to?
八つ当たりは問題外
Venting is out of the question.
どうしようもないこと多すぎ Everyday
Too many things I can't do anything about, everyday.
どうしようもないヨ Everyday
It's hopeless, Everyday
現実（リアル）は手強い
Reality is tough
だけど試練の向こうへ
But I'll go beyond the trials
ため息ついてここから
Starting from here with a sigh
立ち上がれたらまた
If I can stand up again,
なにかが始まる
Something will begin
going now! going now! がむしゃら君に
going now! going now! Recklessly to you
どこへだって繰り出して
Setting out to anywhere
胸張って楽しんじゃおう Up and down
Stand tall and let's have fun, Up and down
Say Everyone
going now! going now! 蹴散らしちゃえよ
going now! going now! Kick it all away
そういう　あいう　波乱万丈
That kind of ups and downs
大体の運命
Most of destiny,
変えてくのは自分だって
it's you who changes it
キミは知ってる
You know that
電車で割り込み
Cutting in line on the train,
コンビニで傘無くなった
lost my umbrella at the convenience store
ジリジリ減っているハートの残機
The remaining lives of my heart are slowly decreasing
あとどれくらい？
How much more?
辻褄合ってなくていい
It doesn't have to make sense
悲劇の１秒先で
Just one second past the tragedy
思い切り笑ったら
If you laugh with all your heart,
いい日に格上げ
it's upgraded to a good day
Let's get it going now! going now! 顔上げてほら
Let's get it going now! going now! Look up, see?
ありのままのステップで
With your natural steps
予測不能な未来を　踏み出して
Step out into an unpredictable future
Say Everyone
going now! going now! 吹き飛ばしちゃえ
going now! going now! Blow it all away
冴えない　浮かない顔した
With that dull, gloomy face
今日なんて全部
Everything about today,
自分だけがそう出来るって
only you can make it happen
キミは知ってる
You know that
I will try it again!
分かってるはずさ
You should know that
I will try it again!
ひらかれるはずさ
It should be opened
今はまだ遠い　そんな景色
That scenery is still far away
怖くても　眩しくても
Even if it's scary or dazzling
この手で掴めるまで…
Until I can grasp it with these hands...
Let's get it going now! going now! がむしゃら君に
Let's get it going now! going now! Recklessly to you
どこへだって繰り出して
Setting out to anywhere
胸張って楽しんじゃおう Up and down
Stand tall and let's have fun, Up and down
Say Everyone
逃げない！しげない！あきらめないで！
Don't run! Don't lose! Don't give up!
そういう　あいう　波乱万丈
That kind of ups and downs
大体の運命
Most of destiny,
変えてくのは自分
it's you who changes it
さあ　どうするんだ
Now, what will you do?
ハッピーチューンの奏で方
The way to play a happy tune
キミは知ってる
You know that
はーい！『キミにまつわる運命事情』でしたー！
Hi! That was 'Kimi ni Matsuwaru Unmei Jijo'!
そして、スネアドラムのスペシャルパフォーマンスでした。ありがとうございました！
And that was the snare drum special performance. Thank you so much!
そして、太鼓隊、集まれー！パン！
And now, drum corps, assemble! Bam!
お、お、あ、あれ？
Oh, oh, ah, huh?
一人減ったな。一人減ったな（笑）
One person left. One person left (laughs).
はい、ということでめちゃめちゃかっこいいパフォーマンス、ありがとう！イエーイ！
Alright, thank you for that amazing performance! Yay!
じゃあね！バイバイ！
See ya! Bye bye!
ふぅ。めちゃめちゃかっこよかったでしょう？
Phew. That was really cool, wasn't it?
よし！５周年ライブ、まだまだ続くからね！
Alright! The 5th anniversary live continues!
アキロゼ、ちょっとお帽子外してくるから、ちょっと待っててね！
AkiRose is going to take off this hat for a bit, so please wait a moment!
よし！
Alright!
まだまだ盛り上がっていく準備、できてるかー！？
Are you ready to keep getting hyped!?
アキロゼ５周年ライブ、ここから、まだまだ盛り上げていくよ！
AkiRose 5th anniversary live, we're going to keep the hype going from here!
それでは、次の曲はこれだ！
Now, here's the next song!
Make a step Make a step Yeah 小宵はバラ色のナイト
Make a step Make a step Yeah Tonight is a rose-colored night
奇妙をのせて　踊りましょう
Carry the strange along and let's dance
アローナ！
Alona!
なんだって フレーバー シレイバー 隠した思い
Whatever flavor, whatever flavor, hidden thoughts
月が綺麗ね ロマンティック
The moon is beautiful, isn't it? Romantic
罪には 甘く フレーバー 果実のように
Sin is sweet, flavor like a fruit
君にそっと ささやくの
I'll whisper softly to you
情熱のソース
Passion source
...ねえ
...Hey
本当の姿を見せて ほら
Show your true self, come on
Give me Gimme Love Give me Gimme Love
私の全てを奪って
Take all of me
Crazy in Crazy in Love Crazy in Crazy in Love
本気見せてあげる
I'll show you my seriousness
アブラカタブラ アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra, abracadabra
君と出会えた奇跡に
In the miracle of meeting you
アブラカタブラ アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra, abracadabra
愛を込めて踊りましょう
Let's dance with love
怒って笑って悩んで迷える日々もなんて素敵なドラマティック
Days of anger, laughter, worry, and hesitation are such a wonderful drama
そうやって探って感じて重ね合わせて君にちょっと近づくの
That's how I explore, feel, and put things together to get a little closer to you
鼓動が叫ぶくらい ほら
Look, my heartbeat is screaming
本能で強惹かれて 太陽
Attracted strongly by instinct, Sun
Give me Gimme Love Give me Gimme Love
溶かしてあげるわ 全て
I'll melt everything for you
fall in fall in Love fall in fall in Love
夢中 止められないの
Hooked, I can't stop
アブラカタブラ アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra, abracadabra
こんな素晴らしい世界に
In such a wonderful world
アブラカタブラ アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra, abracadabra
君のために舞いましょう
Let's dance for you
もう ギリギリでギリギリな 私の心を
Already, my heart is at its limit
ベイビー 君だけに君だけに 全部届けたいよ もっと
Baby, I want to deliver everything to you, only you, even more
Give me Gimme Love Give me Gimme Love
私の全てを奪って
Take all of me
Crazy in Crazy in Love Crazy in Crazy in Love
本気見せてあげる
I'll show you my seriousness
アブラカタブラ アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra, abracadabra
君と出会えた奇跡に
In the miracle of meeting you
アブラカタブラ アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra, abracadabra
愛を込めて踊りましょう
Let's dance with love
アロハナ
Aloha-na
さあさあさあさあ！
Come on, come on, come on!
テンションも上がってきた？
Is your excitement building?
アキロゼはテンションも息も上がってるぞ！
AkiRose's excitement and breath are both rising!
さあ、まだまだ続くけど、次の曲、何かわかるよね？
Now, it's still continuing, but do you know what the next song is?
ヒロインオーディション！
Heroine Audition!
君のヒロインはだあれ？
Who is your heroine?
覚えてる 優しい君の言葉にキュンとして
I remember your kind words made my heart skip a beat
上手く言えない代わりに笑いかけてみたの
Instead of being able to say it well, I tried to smile at you
目があった気がした それだけで
I felt like our eyes met, just from that
言の葉 跳ねた お願い
Words bounced, please
勘違いじゃありませんように
I hope it wasn't a misunderstanding
そっと心の中で熱い視線送った
Quietly in my heart, I sent you a hot gaze
振り向いて願っちゃってたんだ
I was wishing you'd turn around
ヒロインオーディション エントリーしたら私
If I enter the Heroine Audition, will I be the one?
選んでくれるかな
I wonder if you'll choose me
真面目な性格 おはようだけで伝わるよ
Your serious personality comes through just with a "good morning"
何気ない呟き もしかして
A casual mutter, could it be?
見てときどき期待してる
Look, sometimes I'm full of expectation.
眩しい素敵な人ばかりで
Because there are so many dazzling and wonderful people.
自信もなくて　それでも本音では
I don't have confidence, but in my true heart...
365日もっと近付きたい
Every day of the year, I want to get closer.
私なりのペースになるけど
It will be at my own pace, though.
ヒロインオーディション勇気を出したら君は
Heroine Audition, if I show some courage, will you...
ねえ応えてくれるかな
...hey, give me an answer?
出会った一瞬てかなりすごいミラクル
The moment we met was quite a incredible miracle.
このチャンスは赤い糸
This chance is our red thread of fate.
ギュッと手繰り寄せて運命にしよう
Let's pull it tight and make it our destiny.
信じてまっすぐ背伸び言葉にして
Believe, stand tall, and put it into words.
君のヒロインは誰？
Who is your heroine?
きっと君の心を動かしてみせるよ
I'll surely move your heart.
まだまだ全然足りないけど
It's still not nearly enough.
ヒロインオーディション選んでそして私を
Heroine Audition, choose me, and then...
いつかギュッとしてほしい
...I want you to hold me tight someday.
ありがとうずっと大好きだよ
Thank you, I'll love you forever.
2018/06/01 Mirative Debut
12月05日 Hololive announcement due to a traffic accident.
December 5: Hololive announcement due to a traffic accident.
New challenger appears!
Will try my best to express my love and gratitude.
自己紹介をお願いします
Please introduce yourself.
口をきくという宝物が戻ったのがアキロゼからみんなへのプレゼント。これからも一緒に旅してくれる？
The treasure of being able to speak returning is Akirose's gift to everyone. Will you continue this journey with me?
コンタス ハレイリヤ オン シャルイース
Kontas hareiriya on Shallies
アニミターポ ティマイジ ユーリック
Animitaapo timaizi yuurikku
ゼクロクス オクノ クレスティナ オケティ
Zekurokusu okuno kuresutina oketi
ハプアミューキル シャルベイル
Hapuamyuukiru sharubeiru
ヤイーディリ ラレミランサクチュ
Yaiidiri raremiransakuchu
リキナウェミナ スリガディアー
Rikinawemina surigadiaa
ディシーディラスピナ ベーティカス
Dishiidirasupina beetikasu
ディミウォイラシュ モロフワー ハプワー
Dimiwoirashu morofuwahapuwa
コンタス ハレイリヤ オン シャルイース
Kontas hareiriya on Shallies
アニミターポ ティマイジ
Animitaapo timaizi
アローフィア トルムストゥリア
Aroofia torumusturia
ノントシャストゥリア
Nontoshasturia
コンタス ハレイリヤ オン シャルイース
Kontas hareiriya on Shallies
アニムミターポ ティマイジ ユーリック
Animumitaapo timaizi yuurikku
ゼクロクス オクノ クレスティナ オケティ
Zekurokusu okuno kuresutina oketi
ハプアミューキル シャルベイル
Hapuamyuukiru sharubeiru
シャルイース
Shallrys
Esutunari gari viriia
Paratosu toru miatisu romo
Fuuswiniia naitusu
Dererasu mu- gururu
Derelara pipuro nodomoro
Farumo impirarumo mu- sefuri
Onomu-za panira u- darone
Dirawiasarame tekand milarilara
Afisu dasimia
Fimora shero nikonya
Dimimoipono poreyora
Fimora shero rarabira
Kontasu ameria osharuisu
Amumitapotimaitusu
Sekurosu onokuresu tinuyeketi
Hapu amukero sharubeiruo
Modufesanto
Modufekato
Dimimoira chumorobora
Dimimoira chumorobo
Hapua...
はい！
Hi!
アキロゼ5周年Live、Historic ROUTE 5...
Aki Rosenthal 5th Anniversary Live, 'Historic ROUTE 5'...
...ここまで見てくれて、ありがとう、ありがとう！
...thank you so much for watching up until now!
今回は5周年というね、ことで、
Since this is my 5th anniversary,
超スペシャルなマーチングバンドさんとのコラボだったりとか、
we had a super special collaboration with a marching band,
アキロゼのオリジナル曲、新曲も含めて5曲...
as well as 5 of my original songs, including a new one...
それをホロライブのメンバーと一緒に5人でやらせていただきました。
...which I performed with 5 Hololive members.
すごいスペシャルなステージだったと思います。
I think it was a truly special stage.
今日の可愛いスクリーンショットだったり、
I'm eagerly looking forward to your cute screenshots,
可愛い部分の切り抜きとか絶賛待ってるので、
and clips of the cute parts from today's live.
ここ？ ここかな？
Here? Is it here?
「#アキロゼ5周年Live」のハッシュタグをつけて、
Please use the hashtag #AkiRoze5thAnniversaryLive
ぜひぜひいっぱいSNSの海に放出してってください。
and post them all over social media!
待ってるからね！ エゴサするからね！ よろしくお願いします。
I'll be waiting! I'll be ego-searching! Thank you!
さあ、そして、みんなお待ちかね...
And now, for what everyone's been waiting for...
グッズ！ 今回もあります！
Goods! We have them this time too!
それでは紹介動画撮ってきたので、そちらをご覧ください。どうぞ！
I've prepared an introduction video, so please take a look. Here you go!
はい！ アキ・ローゼンタール活動5周年記念グッズ発売決定！
Hi! Aki Rosenthal 5th Anniversary Commemorative Goods are now on sale!
ということで、こちらで詳しくグッズの情報をお知らせしていきたいと思います。
So, I'd like to share more detailed information about the goods here.
まずは、こちら！ 安曇アキタケ先生描き下ろしのビッグタオル！
First up is this! A big towel featuring an illustration by Akitake Azumi-sensei!
これはもうアキロゼとロゼ隊がね、マーチングをしている、
This is a super refreshing and incredibly cute big towel
スーパー爽やかなもうめっちゃ可愛いビッグタオルになっています。
showing Aki-Roze and the Rozetai marching together.
サイズもね、かなり大きめになっているので、
The size is quite large, so
もう飾るも良し、お布団などこう掛けて使うも良し、
you can display it, use it as a blanket on your bed,
普段のね、こう膝掛けとか羽織ったりするのも良し、
or even use it as a lap robe or wrap.
ぜひ使う用、保存用、予備用、などなど...あ、飾る用も忘れてた。
Please get one to use, one to keep, one for backup... oh, and one to display!
ぜひね、いっぱい、いっぱいゲットしてくれたら、めちゃくちゃ嬉しいです！
Please get lots and lots of them, I'd be so happy!
続いて、本日のライブテーマ、Historic ROUTE 5、こちらのロゴアクリルキーホルダー！
Next is the logo acrylic key holder for today's live theme, Historic ROUTE 5!
めちゃくちゃおしゃれなデザインだと思います。もう超おしゃグッズとして、ぜひジャラジャラと見せびらかしてほしいなと思います。
I think it's a very stylish design. I hope you'll carry it around and show it off as a super stylish item.
ちなみに、アキロゼ、4周年記念グッズで出した時のロゴのキーホルダーも、実は同じテイストで揃えさせていただいてます。
By the way, the logo key holder from AkiRose's 4th anniversary is actually made with the same style.
セットの合わせ技なんかもね、めちゃくちゃいいんじゃないかな、エモさもマシマシ、だと思もうので、ぜひゲットしてみてください！
I think they'd look great as a set, and it adds to the sentimental value, so please get one!
そして、そして、続いてのグッズはこちら。マーチングバンド帽子コインケースキーホルダー！
And next, we have this item. The Marching Band Hat Coin Case Key Holder!
めちゃ可愛い、もう。今回のライブロゴがバシッと入り、ふわふわのね、羽もついたようなマーチングバンド帽子のデザインのキーホルダー。
It's so cute. It has this live's logo on it, and it's a marching band hat design with a fluffy feather.
かつ、ファスナーを開けるとコインケースになっているので、日常使いから、お飾りから、もう超万能に使えるスーパーグッズです。
Plus, when you unzip it, it becomes a coin case, so it's a super versatile item for everyday use or decoration.
めちゃ可愛いです。ぜひね、いっぱいゲットしてください。
It's so cute. Please get lots of them.
そして、そして、今回のライブでもアキロゼも頑張って練習したスネアドラムを模した、収納ケースが出ちゃいます。
And next, we're releasing a storage case modeled after the snare drum that AkiRose practiced so hard for this live.
めちゃ可愛い！もう特別なアキロゼ仕様のスネアドラムになっているんですけども、
It's so cute! It's a special AkiRose-version snare drum,
これサイズもしっかりと大きくてね、小物入れとしては優秀なんじゃないかなと思います。
and it's quite large, so I think it'll be great as a storage box for small items.
お家で使うもよし、お店に飾るもよし、見せびらかすもよし、万能に使えると思うので、ぜひぜひ色々と楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいなと思います。
You can use it at home, display it in a store, or just show it off. It's very versatile, so I'd be happy if you enjoyed it in various ways.
そして、こちらの活動5周年記念フルセットをご購入の方、
And for those who purchase the 5th Anniversary Full Set,
なんと、アキ・ローゼンタール直筆サイン入り＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りの
it comes with Aki Rosenthal's handwritten signature and a foil-stamped replica message
安曇アキタケ先生描き下ろしポストカード、さらに、特典ボイスがついてまいります！
on a postcard drawn by Azumi Akitake-sensei, plus a bonus voice track!
特典はあったほうがいいよなあ。ただ直筆サインの方が、今回ちょっと数量限定でお届けになります。
Bonuses are always good to have, right? However, the one with the handwritten signature will be available in limited quantities.
ただ、数量限定じゃない方のフルセットにも、特典ボイス、そして箔押しのサインとメッセージはついてまいりますので、
But even the non-limited full set includes the bonus voice track and the foil-stamped signature and message,
ぜひぜひたくさんね、記念にゲットしていただけるとすごく嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします。
so I'd be very happy if you'd get them to commemorate this anniversary. Thank you.
ぜひ、詳細情報など、まだチェックしてない人は、ポチポチっと今のうちに準備しておいてください。
If you haven't checked the details yet, please do so now and get ready.
5周年記念グッズということで、いっぱい考えて、悩んで、愛情込めてね、用意したグッズなので、ぜひよろしくお願いします。
Since these are 5th-anniversary goods, I've put a lot of thought and love into preparing them, so please check them out.
はーい、ということで、記念ライブもすごく可愛いグッズなので、絶対、絶対、絶対、絶対ゲットしてください。
Okay, the anniversary live goods are so cute, so please, please, please get them.
概要欄をチェックチェック！
Check the description box!
はい。そして、今日はね、5周年というスペシャルな日なので、ちょっと恥ずかしいんですが、
Yes. And since today is a special day—the 5th anniversary—it's a bit embarrassing, but...
いつもね、あんまりあきちゃん本音を言うの苦手だから、
Aki-chan is usually not very good at expressing her true feelings,
今日は手紙にまとめて書いてきたので、ロゼ隊に向けてちょっと読ませてもらってもいいですか？
so I wrote them down in a letter today. May I read it to the Rosetai?
恥ずかしいな。ふー。じゃあ、聴いてください。
This is embarrassing. *Exhales* Okay, please listen.
ロゼ隊へ
To the Rosetai
今日はホロライブでデビューしてまるっと5年。
Today marks exactly five years since my debut with Hololive.
いつもよりちょっとだけ特別な日なので、手紙を書きました。
Since it's a slightly more special day than usual, I wrote a letter.
うまく言葉にして伝えられるかわからないけど、聴いてくれると嬉しいです。
I don't know if I can express it well in words, but I'd be happy if you'd listen.
もう5年。そんなに経つんだとびっくりしちゃうね。
It's already been five years. It's surprising how much time has passed.
アキロゼ、少しは成長できたかな。
I wonder if AkiRose has grown a little.
日々活動してると、ふとした瞬間悲しくなったり、
In my daily activities, there are moments when I suddenly feel sad
苦しくなったりすることがあります。
or go through hard times.
そんな時いつも勇気を振り絞れるのは、ロゼ隊のおかげです。
In those moments, the reason I'm always able to muster up courage is thanks to the Rosetai.
あの日出会った時からずっとそばにいてくれる君も、
To those of you who have been by my side since we met that day,
今初めてアキロゼを見つけてくれた君も、
and to those of you who have just found AkiRose for the first time...
アキロゼと出会って...
meeting AkiRose...
好きになってくれて
Thank you for liking me...
ありがとう。
...thank you.
アキロゼは...
Aki-Rose...
...得意なことが多くはありません。
...doesn't have many things she's good at.
人前で目立つことをするのも...
Being the center of attention...
...どちらかというと苦手です。
...is something I'm rather bad at.
乱暴な強い言葉もネタだとしても言えなかったり、
Even as a joke, I can't say harsh or strong words,
甘えたり頼ったりすることも苦手だし、
and I'm not good at acting spoiled or relying on others,
コミュニケーションも苦手だし、
and I'm bad at communicating, too.
本当に不器用な塊だなって思ってます。
I truly feel like I'm a bundle of clumsiness.
そして、そんな自分でいたくないから...
And because I didn't want to be that way...
...取り繕ったりとか、
...I've tried to put up a front,
変に強がって平気なふりをしたり、
unnecessarily acting tough and pretending everything's fine,
虚勢を張って生きてきちゃったなって、
and living with a bluff,
よく思います。
I often think about that.
それはVTuberとしてデビューしてからも一緒で、
It's been the same even after debuting as a VTuber,
だからこそ自分を好きでいることが...
and that's exactly why liking myself...
...とても難しい。
...is very difficult.
そう思っちゃうこともよくあります。
I often find myself thinking that.
だけど、そんな時にいつも救われるのが、
But what always saves me at those times,
ロゼ隊の言葉や応援です。
is the words and support from the Rose-tai.
自分が嫌いなところも好きだって褒めてくれたり、
You compliment me by saying you even like the parts of me I hate,
認めてくれたり、
you accept me,
そばにいてくれたり、
you stay by my side,
一緒に過ごす時間を楽しんでくれたり...
you enjoy the time we spend together...
ちょっとだけ自分のことが好きになれます。
I can come to like myself just a little bit more.
だから、いつも...
So, as always...
...ありがとう。
...thank you.
アキロゼはみんなの日々の生活に...
Aki-Rose wants to deliver a time...
...彩りを飾るような時間を届けていきたいと、
...that adds color to everyone's daily lives,
ずっとずっと思っています。
and I've always, always thought that.
それは今でも変わりません。
That hasn't changed even now.
そしてなるべく長く、
And I want to stay by your side,
ずっとそばにいたいと思っています。
as long as possible, forever.
5周年を迎えて、6年目に突入します。
With the 5th anniversary, I'm entering my 6th year.
この1年、もしかしたら急に変わったことはできないかもしれない。
In this coming year, I might not be able to change suddenly.
だけど、私、6年目は...
But for my 6th year...
...等身大の自分を受け入れながら、
...while accepting my true self,
ロゼ隊、そしてホロライブのみんなと一緒に、
together with the Rose-tai and everyone in Hololive,
楽しい時間をいっぱい作っていきたいなと思います！
I want to create many fun times!
今日もまた新しい景色が見れたと思います！
I think I saw a new landscape again today!
これからも1つずつ、一歩ずつ、いろんな景色を見ていこうね！
Let's keep seeing various sights, one by one, step by step!
いや、見せていくので、アキロゼと一緒に、
No, I'll show them to you, so together with Aki-Rose,
手をつないでのんびり散歩しながら楽しんでいこうね！
let's enjoy ourselves while taking a leisurely stroll hand-in-hand!
アキロゼより。
From Aki-Rose.
はい、でした。
Yes, that was it.
本当にたくさんの、いろんな思いがあるけど、
There are so many different feelings, but...
こうして、みんなの前で立っていられること、
...being able to stand before you all like this,
すごくすごく嬉しいです。
makes me very, very happy.
6年目もよろしくお願いします。
I look forward to your support in my 6th year as well.
ということで、アキロゼ、
And so, Aki-Rose,
そしてロゼ隊のみんな、そして今日、
and all of you in the Rose-tai, today,
明日、明後日、この未来も、アキロゼと出会ってくれるロゼ隊、
tomorrow, the day after, and in this future, the Rose-tai who meet Aki-Rose,
よろしくね！
please stick with me!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
すごい楽しいライブだった、本当にありがとう。
It was a really fun live, thank you so much.
さて、もうラスト締めていかないといけない。
Well, I have to wrap things up now.
すごい寂しいけども、
I'm very sad to do so, but...
いろいろお知らせしようと思います。
I have some announcements for you.
今日、このライブ終わった後、
Today, after this live is over,
いつもはメンバー限定でね、アフターライブとかやったりするんだけど、
usually I'd do an after-live stream for members only,
今日はこの後、22時30分から、
but today, after this, from 22:30,
普通のね、YouTubeのライブで、
on a regular YouTube stream,
今日のこの感想だったりとか、色々話していきたいなと思って...
I'd like to talk about my thoughts on today and various other things...
いるので、
...so,
ぜひぜひ遊びに来てください。
please, please come and visit.
チャンネル登録、高評価、通知オン、パチッ、
Please subscribe, like, and turn on notifications,
まだの人はよろしくお願いします。
if you haven't already!
それでは、本当に本当に
Well then, really, really...
5周年ありがとう！
thank you for the 5th anniversary!
6年目もよろしくね！
I'm looking forward to the 6th year, too!
ろくー！
Six!
バイバイー！
Bye-bye!
Aki Rosenthal
Historic ROUTE FIVE
Historic ROUTE 5
Aki Rosenthal 5th Anniversary 3DLIVE
アキロゼ5周年記念ライブ
Akirose 5th Anniversary Live